

Bergamo, Italy



https://marcobacis.com



marc.bacis@gmail.com



marcobacis



marcobacis

## Skills

- C#/.NET
- C/C++
- Python
- Azure
- Qt
- Git
- Docker
- Unity

# Languages

- · Italian- Native
- English- Advanced (C1)
- French- Basic (A2)

# Marco Bacis

### Software Engineer

#### About

Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience and a M.Sc. from Politecnico di Milano. I have a diverse experience in frontend/desktop applications (WPF, Qt, Unity, React) backend systems (C#/.NET) and a bit of low-level systems (C++).

Looking for new experiences as a full-stack developer with a broader view and more responsibilities.

Quick learner and passionate about staying up-to-date with new technologies, recently started to participate in tech communities (meetups and conferences) and writing a blog about my experiences.

### **Experience**

Software Engineer @ e-Novia S.p.A.

Milan

Sep 2019 - Today

Working in the Software Engineering team of e-Novia (the "Enterprises Factory"), supporting the company controlled startups in different areas (robotics, mechanics, web, etc...) along with some external corporate customers.

Worked on different projects and technologies in a variety of fields:

- Web and IoT platforms (React, .NET, C++)
- Desktop Applications for industrial settings (Qt/WPF, C#, C++)
- Augmented/Virtual Reality (Unity)

#### Tutor @ Politecnico di Milano

Milan

Mar 2019 - Jun 2019

Tutor for the IEIM course (Computer Science for Biomedical Eng. students, C language) and "Prova Finale" course (Software Engineering final project course, Java/OOP concepts etc..) at Politecnico di Milano during the second semester A.Y. 2018/2019.

#### Software Engineering Intern @ Maxeler Technologies

London

Mar 2017 - Sep 2017

Internship in the Machine Learning team:

- Design and analysis of ML algorithms for DFE (Java / FPGA-based) acceleration
- Accelerator integration in a pipelined architecture for facial recognition
- Tuning of the accelerator to reach high performances (published a paper at ICCD 2017)

## **Education**

M.Sc. CS&Engineering (110 cum laude)

Politecnico di Milano

2016-2019

Thesis: BlastFunction: an FPGA-as-a-Service system for Accelerated Serverless Computing

B.Sc. CS&Engineering (106/110)

Politecnico di Milano

2013-2016

Final Project: Implementation of the "Council of Four" board game in Java